healthination.com 2019-12-07

# Healthination - Privacy Policy

Welcome to www.healthination.com (the “Website(s), referred to herein sometimes collectively as either the “Website” or “Website(s)”), owned and operated by HealthiNation, a Delaware corporation headquartered in New York (“HealthiNation”, “we”, “our”, or “us”). This Website is intended for use only by residents of the United States. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) is intended to inform you about how HealthiNation collects, uses and discloses information that you may provide to the Website, including your personally identifiable information (“PII”). Please be sure to read this entire Policy before using or submitting information to the Website.  
By using the Website, you agree to the terms of this Policy and consent to the collection and use of your information as described herein. If you do not agree with this Policy, please do not use the Website.

**1\. How does the Website Work?**

The Website offers various health-related information to anonymous browsers and users who voluntarily provide us with certain information, including PII (collectively “you” or “your”) in connection with access. You do not have to provide any PII to us in order to use the Website, but you may voluntarily submit certain PII if, for instance, you wish to receive our newsletters or wish us to respond to a request. HealthiNation may need to change this Policy and how we handle PII from time to time in order to address new issues, evolving technologies, changes on our sites, or business practices. HealthiNation will post those changes so you will always know what information we gather and how we might use that information. Please refer back to this Policy regularly.

**2\. What type of PII does HealthiNation collect from you and how do we use it?**

As stated above, you may provide certain PII to HealthiNation in order to have access to certain features on our Website(s). Such PII shall include basic biographical and contact information, e.g., your name, address and email address. We may also ask you for general statistical, non-PII about yourself and your interests. Unless you provide PII to HealthiNation through the Website, we do not collect any PII from you. HealthiNation may provide your PII to various entities who work on behalf of or with us. These entities may use your PII to help us fulfill your requests in connection with our Website(s) and to help us communicate with you about different resources offered as part of the Website(s). For example, we may transfer information collected at registration, including PII, to service providers and other third parties who assist us in running the Website, and/or third party vendors in order to execute transactions requested by you. We will require these entities to agree to treat your PII in accordance with this Policy.  
HealthiNation values your trust. HealthiNation does not share any of your PII with any third parties for direct marketing or other related purposes, and only uses this information to service your opt-in requests, such as receiving our HealthiNation newsletters, or for uses specified at the point of collection.

**3\. Under what circumstances may we release PII?**

We may release your PII if we believe such release is necessary to comply with the law (e.g., a legal process or a statutory authorization), to apply or enforce our customer agreements, to protect our rights or property, to protect Website users from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of the Website, or if we reasonably believe that a danger to any person requires disclosure of such PII.

You acknowledge that HealthiNation is located in the United States of America (“U.S.”) and processes and stores your information in the U.S., and that as a result, U.S. governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through the laws of the U.S.

**4\. What other information does HealthiNation collect?**

We also collect anonymous and aggregate information from you about your preferences in navigating the Website by using cookies, action tags and other methods. Your Internet browser automatically transmits to the Website some of this anonymous information. Cookies are small text files that identify your computer. We may use cookies to, among other things, monitor Website usage, customize Website features, identify your computer’s operating system and browser, and complete transactions. An action tag is a small, graphic image on a webpage that is designed to allow the website owner or a third party to monitor who is visiting a website by collecting certain information, such as the IP address of the computer to which the tag is sent, the URL of the webpage that the tag comes from and the time that such webpage was viewed. Tags may be associated with cookie information. We may also use such anonymous and aggregate information for promotional purposes.  
We currently utilize Google Analytics to analyze the audience of the Website and improve our content. No personal information is collected from Google Analytics. For further information on the privacy policy concerning Google Analytics, please go here, https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl+en.  
We may use plugins, such as Facebook or Twitter. Each plug-in is the responsibility of its provider and we have no control over the amount of information that the respective provider collects with the help of its own plugin, or how it uses that information. If you are not yet a customer of the provider or have not (yet) consented there to having your data collected and used, we recommend not clicking on these plugins. If, on the other hand, you are already a customer of the plugin provider, you should refer directly to the relevant provider for information on the kind and amount of personal data it collects and uses, and for what purpose. You should also refer to the relevant provider for information about the data they provide to third parties and the permitted uses of such information.

**5\. What information does HealthiNation allow its advertising partners to collect?**

Third-party cookies are used for targeting and retargeting of online advertising. Third-party cookies are also used for measurement and analysis of audience data including market research.  
HealthiNation incorporates third-party cookies to collect usage data for the purposes of targeting advertising on HealthiNation website and partner properties, and for retargeting advertising to visitors after they leave HealthiNation properties as well. Should consumers want to opt-out of tracking with these third-party cookies or simply find more information about entities involved in online advertising, HealthiNation encourages users to visit the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) website at http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp and the Digital Advertising Alliance website at http://aboutads.info.  
HealthiNation incorporates additional third-party cookies for the purposes of market research, as we track audience data for measurement of demographic, geographic, and other similar attributes. These types of cookies cannot be individually opted-out; users that do not want to be tracked should use the “Private Browsing” and/or “Do Not Track” feature in their web browser. To learn more about cookies and how to specify your preferences, you can search for “cookie” in the “Help” portion of your browser.

**6\. What types of targeted ads might be shown as the result of third-party advertising tracking?**

Ads appearing on our web sites may be delivered to you on behalf of HealthiNation as well as any of our third-party advertising companies. Information about your visits to our sites, such as the number of times you have viewed an ad, date/time at which the ads were shown, the advertisers’ cookies, and the IP address of the computer you use (but not your address or other Personally Identifiable Information) is used to serve ads to you on our sites. We share web site usage information about visitors to our sites with these companies for the purposes of managing and targeting advertisements, measuring their effectiveness, and for market research analysis on our sites. For these purposes, we and the third-party advertising companies that we use may note some of the pages you visit on our sites.

**7\. What types of cookies might be used?**

In order to track your use of our sites, “cookies” are employed. We may use two types of cookies — so-called “browser cookies” and “Flash cookies”. Browser cookies (also called “HTTP cookies”) are pieces of information that are sent by web sites and stored in your computer’s hard drive, which provide you a service by allowing us to recognize your computer to save you from having to re-enter the same data every time you visit our web sites. They also allow us to learn how visitors use our web sites. This user data is aggregated for tracking purposes primarily by tallying pages viewed throughout our web sites and logging Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses, browser types, general geographic origin of access to our sites and similar aggregated usage data. Flash cookies (also called “Locally Stored Objects” or “LSOs”) work in a similar manner to browser cookies and are also used to remember settings and preferences and to track usage. However, they relate to certain Flash content such as animations, quizzes, interactive features, and videos, are stored differently on your hard drive and are managed through a different interface than the one provided by your web browser. In general, Flash cookies are more persistent and can store more data than browser cookies.

**8\. I really don’t want my page visits to be tracked at all. How do I disable tracking again?**

As described above, in the course of serving advertisements to the site, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a browser or Flash cookie on your hard drive. However, if you turn cookies off (whether browser or Flash cookies), you will not have access to some HealthiNation features and services.

  * If you do not want to receive browser cookies, you may set your browser to reject them.
  * If you wish to disable or delete Flash cookies, you should consult the Help file for your Flash application.
  * If you want to fully opt-out of all tracking, HealthiNation recommends that you use the “Private Browsing” and/or “Do Not Track” features of your browser.

To learn more about cookies and how to specify your preferences, you can search for “cookie” in the “Help” portion of your browser.

**9\. Who stores the PII information we collect for our email newsletter?**

HealthiNation maintains a secure database, via our email database service provider, in which we store the user information you may provide to us. We contract with email database service providers in order to distribute our electronic newsletters. Therefore, if you opt in to receive our newsletter, your email address is shared with and housed on the email service providers’ database(s).  
10\. How do we store information and how long do we store it?

HealthiNation takes steps consistent with commercially reasonable industry standards to secure any PII collected from you from loss, misuse, unauthorized access and destruction while under our control. Please note that despite our efforts to protect information provided to us, we cannot guarantee that such information will not be lost, disclosed or accessed by accidental circumstances or by the unauthorized acts of others. You should know and consider that no Internet transmission is ever completely secure or error-free. HealthiNation stores the information you provide to us in an active database in perpetuity, subject to our discretion, unless you opt-out.

**11\. Does HealthiNation provide links to other websites?**

HealthiNation may provide links to other websites or resources of possible interest to you. Because we have no control over such websites or resources, the collection and use of your PII and other information by such websites shall be subject to the policies and procedures of such websites and not this Privacy Policy. You should consult privacy policies for all other sites, as HealthiNation has no control over information submitted to or collected by such third parties.

HealthiNation sometimes offers contests, sweepstakes, or promotions sponsored or co-sponsored by third parties. These third parties may obtain PII that visitors voluntarily submit to participate in the contest, sweepstakes, or promotion. HealthiNation has no control over the third-party sponsor’s use of this information. The Website will notify you at the time of requesting PII if third-party sponsors will be provided with such information.

**12\. What are our policies regarding children?**

The Website is not intended for children under the age of thirteen (13). HealthiNation does not knowingly collect or solicit PII from anyone under the age of thirteen. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible.

**13\. What are our policies regarding California residents?**

In accordance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act, we may collect certain PII when you use the Website. California law permits users who are California residents to periodically request and obtain certain information about any PII disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and wish to make such a request or wish for us to refrain from gathering your PII, please submit your request in writing to privacy@healthination.com.

**14\. What are our policies regarding EU residents?**

As stated in this privacy policy, the Website is intended for use only by United States residents. GDPR provides certain rights for EU residents. EU residents may decline to share certain information with us, in which case we may not be able to provide some of the features and functionality of the services. These rights include, in accordance with applicable law, the right to object to or request the restriction of processing of your information, and to request access to, rectification, erasure and portability of your own information. Where we process your information on the basis of your consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent (noting that such withdrawal does not affect the lawfulness of any processing performed prior to the date on which we receive notice of such withdrawal, and does not prevent the processing of your PII in reliance upon any other available legal bases). Requests should be submitted by contacting us in writing to privacy@healthination.com. If you are an EU resident and have any unresolved privacy concern, you have the right to contact the appropriate EU Supervisory Authority and lodge a complaint.

**15\. Do we have a mechanism to address the removal, change of, or amendment to PII and complaints about the handling of information that we collect?**

If you wish to remove, change or amend the PII that you have submitted to HealthiNation, please send us an email requesting such removal, change or amendment to privacy@healthination.com. If you have questions or concerns about any of our information collection or handling practices, please contact us at privacy@healthination.com.

**Last updated on August 22, 2019**

* * *

Terms & Conditions – Privacy policy – Editorial Policy

* * *
